Joe Dodgson

68 Main Street
Dickens Heath, Solihull
B90 1UA
+447805 984 510
j.dodgson@live.co.uk
LinkedIn

Personal Profile

Full-stack web developer with engineering background, educated at University of Nottingham achieving a first class MEng (Hons) Degree in Civil Engineering. Recently earned a certificate in full-stack development from the University of Birmingham, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design. Can interpret requirements to implement appropriate solutions, breaking complex problems down into small steps. An able communicator, having presented ideas and engineering solutions to colleagues, clients and stakeholders. I have a passion for problem solving and developing solutions which deliver automation and enhance user experience. I thrive when applying mathematical and analytical reasoning skills to develop solutions to problems. My proudest achievement as a developer was working with peers to successfully deliver a reading list organiser application. I am excited to apply my skills and learn more as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team to build better experiences for web users.

Education

Mar 2020 – Sep 2020, University of Birmingham and Trilogy ES, UK, Coding Bootcamp

- Front and back end development with a focus on JavaScript technologies (React, Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, HTML and CSS)
- API interaction, git version control best practices and agile work methodologies
- Curriculum developed and taught by industry practitioners

Sept 2011 – July 2016, University of Nottingham, UK, MEng (Hons) Civil Engineering

- 5 Year MEng Civil Engineering Degree including:
 - 1 year of study abroad at UoN's Malaysia Campus
 - 1 year industrial placement at North Midland Construction
- Graduated with a First Class degree

Experience

Sept 2016 – Present, Arup, Rail Engineer / Embedded Developer

- HS2 Phase 2B: Product Manager for development of a report automation tool to manage input data and aid delivery of over 500 technical design reports
- Crossrail 2: Plan and profile drawing automation. Developed and implemented a workflow to automate the creation of over 100 plan and profile drawings as part of the track alignment submission.
- Track Compliance Tool. Working closely with the tool developer to test and provide feedback on the functionality and user experience

July 2015 – Sept 2015, University of Nottingham, Research Placement

- Research on the application of InSAR (using satellite data to measure line of site distance to the earth) to monitor ground subsidence and its effect on railway infrastructure.
- Presented my research findings and advice for future research to several senior academics and industry professionals.